

+45 70 71 03 23 rasmus@borgsmidt.dk linkedin.com/in/borgsmidt github.com/borgsmidt

References available upon request

Rasmus Borgsmidt

Sr Software Engineer, B.Sc. in Computer Science

ABOUT ME Born 1975 and grew up in the Copenhagen area » Tinkering with computers since the 1980s » Bachelor of Computer Science from University of Copenhagen » Hired into Adaytum in 1997, then acquired by Cognos in 2003 and IBM in 2009 » 15+ years of experience building financial planning software for the enterprise » Worked on numerous projects and technologies, ranging from bare-metal machine coding to high-level object-oriented, functional and array languages » Named inventor and co-inventor on several issued patents » Lived abroad a number of years in the UK and Luxembourg » Married, father of three, currently based in Copenhagen

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr Software Engineer, IBM, 2009-present

In this role, my primary responsibility is refining and maintaining the calc engine at the heart of the *IBM Cognos Planning* enterprise software solution. I also contribute to the development of other related products and occasionally visit customer sites for beta testing and the like.

Scrum Master for Distributed Team, IBM, 2009–2012

In addition to my development responsibilities, I served as *Team Captain* of a highly distributed scrum team with members across four time zones.

Sr Software Engineer, Cognos, 2003–2008

In this role, my primary responsibility was building and maintaining core server components of the *Cognos Planning* enterprise software solution. In addition to this, I was heavily involved in research projects that later resulted in a series of patents.

QA Technician / Software Engineer, Adaytum, 1997-2002

In my initial role at Adaytum, I worked in 3rd-level support and with test bed development. Later my responsibilities shifted and I started contributing directly to the *Adaytum Planning* software product.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. in Computer Science, University of Copenhagen, 2010-2014

A bachelor's thesis was submitted June 2013 and was graded 12 (top mark). The thesis titled *Functional Array Programming Compiled to a Virtual Machine* is available upon request.

B.Sc. in Computer Science, Maths, University of Copenhagen, 1994–1998 First attempt at this degree was cut short after being hired into Adaytum in 1997.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING Experience with a host of languages, such as Java, Ruby, C#, JavaScript, Haskell, SML, Erlang, C, Python, J/APL, MSIL, Java Bytecode, assembly language, binary machine code—the list goes on.

METHODOLOGY Keen proponent of *outside-in* design principles, such as test-driven development, and the importance of small teams, incremental delivery and iterative processes in general. Respects the art and craft of software engineering, and takes pride in continuous integration and refactoring.

LANGUAGES Speaks and writes Danish and English with native proficiency, German with elementary proficiency.

PERSONALITY

TRAITS Always curious, generally well-liked, can have a meaningful conversation with people from all walks of life. Handles pressure well and makes a point of doing things the right way.

INTERESTS Concurrent Programming (Erlang/OTP) » Dynamic and functional languages » Building grammars and DSLs » Cloud technologies » Network security and anonymity » Tinkering with Raspberry Pi » Photography » Classic computer emulation » Go (ancient strategic board game)

PATENTS

Scalable mechanism for resolving cell-level access from sets of dimensional access rules, 2013, uspatno. 8,538,990

Techniques for resolving cell-level access in a multi-dimensional data structure based on one or more sets of dimensional access rules.

Rasmus Borgsmidt, David Bowen, Kirk Bates

Automatically moving annotations associated with multi-dimensional data between live data cubes, 2013, uspatno. 8,347,207

Techniques for sharing multi-dimensional data and associated annotations between software systems.

Rasmus Borgsmidt, Finuala Barnes, Bindhu Cherian

Enterprise planning and performance management system providing type-safe retrieval of multi-dimensional data, 2011, uspatno. 7,895,150

Techniques for ensuring type safety at compile time of multi-dimensional data retrieval.

Rasmus Borgsmidt, Michael Gould

Job scheduling for automatic movement of multi-dimensional data between live data cubes, 2011, uspatno. 7,877,355

Techniques for sharing multi-dimensional data between software systems.

Rasmus Borgsmidt, David Bowen

Virtual multi-dimensional datasets for enterprise software systems, 2010, uspatno. 7,747,562

Techniques for specifying virtual datasets within an enterprise software system. Rasmus Borgsmidt, Michael Gould

Multi-dimensional data cube validation, 2009, uspatno. 7,610,294

Techniques for validating data that a user enters into a multi-dimensional data cube within an enterprise software system.

Rasmus Borgsmidt